This is the important bottle that
Ioryogi gave me for passing the test.
When this bottle is filled, my wish will come true and I'll finally be able to go there.
Right, Ioryogi?
When do you think that will be?
I'm looking forward to it, Ioryogi!
You know...
You're the one who's going to fill it up, Kobato!
Kobato.
How do I do this again?
The simplest things in life
end up being the most difficult.
I just want to smile when I'm happy
and sing a song whenever I please.
I was told, "Someday, your dream will come true."
But when exactly will that be?
I can't wait that long!
I spread my arms
on the count of one two three
and gather all the light in the world.
Tell me,
isn't there something I can do?
Even if someone hurts my feelings,
I'll keep running toward the light.
Even if I trip, fall, and cry my eyes out, I still believe.
Although it may seem silly...
I believe in tomorrow.
Production
The Kobato Protection Group
Kobato Hanato!
Yes!
...The Konpeito's Shine.
You got it?
Just getting that bottle is nothing.
What are you collecting?
The wounded hearts of people, Ioryogi!
And when you gather those?
I have to heal those wounded hearts!
All right! At least you seem to understand.
Then let's go get them!
Yes!
Ah, I forgot to say something.
You can't speak to me in the human world.
Eh? Why's that?
Since you lack all memories, knowledge and common sense, I'll tell you.
Stuffed animals can't speak here,
so talking to something that can't talk back would be weird, got it?!
Why can't they speak?
Because they're stuffed animals.
Why can't stuffed animals speak?
Just get going!
Right! I'll do my best!
Don't suddenly jump off the see-saw!
Is there anyone here with a wounded heart?
Is there anyone here who wants to be healed?
Please let me heal your heart!
I'm fine, thanks!
Excuse me! Is there anything I can do to heal you?
Jeez.
Is there any way I can be of service?
Rock, paper, scissors!
Hey miss, could you help us?
With what?
When we play kick the can, you can be "it"!
Oh? Would it be helpful if I were "it"?
Yeah, please!
All right, I'll do my best!
Kick the can!
Huh, that's strange. There's nothing in the bottle.
How does being "it" heal anyone?
Nobody's heart would be healed by that.
Really?
All you did was play a game with them.
I see...
I guess it's pretty hard to meet someone who wants their heart to be healed, huh.
But if there's no one that wants to be healed,
then there's no sad person with a
wounded heart! That's a good thing!
Jeez, you put a positive spin on everything.
I wish I could find someone who needs help...
Um... excuse me...
H-Here...
You're giving this... to me?
Yes, please.
To think that you go around to people and hand out wonderful things like this...
What a wonderful person you are!
Come on.
I've still got a lot to get rid of...
It'd be a big help if you'd
take as many as you want.
Really?
Then I'll take them all!
Huh?
Thanks! You saved me!
Not only did I help him, but I
got all of this great stuff too!
What are you gonna do with all that?
Now it's my turn to give these
wonderful things to other people!
Huh?
Here you go! Wonderful tissues!
I'm sure they'll be useful!
Here you go!
Here!
Have some!
I'll give you lots!
I'm good, thanks.
Here!
Please don't hold back!
Wonderful tissues right here!
Jeez.
I'm very sorry!
Hey.
Yes?
Quit fooling around in the middle of the road.
I'm sorry!
He's...
That one guy...
And pick up all those tissues.
Please wait!
Please let me thank you!
I think he went this way...
The sheets went flying!
Miss Sayaka, over here!
What are you doing?
Oh no.
Are you all right?
Yes.
She bruised her nose!
She did!
I'm so embarrassed...
Hey,
you shouldn't be laughing.
Right, Miss Sayaka!
I'm sorry.
I work here at Yomogi Nursery.
We're so understaffed that I even have to do the laundry.
You're understaffed?
Yes...
And it gives you problems?
Well, yes...
Would it help to have more workers?
Well...
Would it help you?
Yes.
I'll help out!
Here, take these!
Thank you.
Hey, what's your name?
I'm Toshihiko!
My name is Kobato Hanato!
Kobato...?
That's a weird name!
Weird name!
I guess so.
So your dad's name must be Obato!
Nope!
So what's his name?
What's his name?
Well...
Hey...
What is it?
You don't have a dad?
Yeah...
We don't care about his name!
Let's go play!
Everyone, don't crowd around her.
Okay, Miss Sayaka!
What would you like me to help out with?
It'd be great if you just kept them busy like that.
Kept them busy...
Um...
Miss Kobato!
Yes?
Play the organ!
I'm sorry, I don't know how to play it.
Oh...
I'm sorry.
But we can all dance together!
You can dance?
Yes!
Wait!
Hey, Mr. Kiyokazu, come play the organ!
We're going to dance together with Miss Kobato!
She's not a teacher.
Then... Kobato!
Why did you follow me?
I just wanted to thank you.
Fine. Go home.
But I'm helping out here!
You can't play the organ.
You're useless.
Oh, are you two...
...friends?
No!
Oh.
This is Kiyokazu Fujimoto.
You'll be working with him.
And this is Kobato.
Please try and get along today.
Okay!
Don't get in my way.
Mr. Kiyokazu, come and play the organ!
Hurry up, teacher!
All right, then I'll leave it up to you two.
Kobato too!
Let's dance!
What's that supposed to be?
He's such a bully!
But I won't give up!
Kobato is funny!
Is this where all the children live?
They don't live here, we just watch them during the day.
Oh, is that so.
But this place is kind of old.
Newer nurseries have opened close by,
so fewer and fewer children come here.
However!
We have to do our best!
There's no point in worrying.
You're right, Fujimoto.
Thanks!
You really helped us out, Kobato.
The children looked like they were really having fun too.
Not at all, I was just playing with them!
That kind of thing always makes Ioryogi mad.
Oh no! Ioryogi's gone!
Was there someone with you?
Yes! Well, I had a stuffed animal with me.
Since he can't talk, I'll have to go get him or else I'll be in big trouble!
Excuse me!
Can I come back tomorrow?
If you can.
Miss Sayaka!
We don't know where she lives or what she does.
Do we really want her around the children?
You do know! I'm Kobato Hanato!
Do you think just knowing your name is enough?
I'm—
What?
I'm trying to find that out myself...
Well...
If you can, you're more than welcome!
But, we won't really be able to pay you...
No! Just being able to help out is a good enough payment for me!
Then we look forward to having you.
Hey.
Yes?
Just one thing.
If you're just doing this out of pity or curiosity, don't come back.
You'll just inconvenience us if you
think that we're pitiful or overworked.
I don't think that at all!
Um...
Cause trouble...
Causing trouble, huh.
How dare you leave me
behind in the middle of town!
I'm glad you found me, Ioryogi!
Don't be!
Do you have any idea what would
have happened if someone took me?!
I'm sorry!
Didn't I tell you? I'm a stuffed animal.
Stuffed animals don't just walk around on their own!
I'm sorry!!
Would you forget the bottle too?!
The bottle?
Of course...
What do you mean, "of course"?
Did ya think there'd be anything in there?
Of course, there was nothing I could do to heal anyone...
In fact...
I wonder if I just caused trouble.
Fujimoto seemed like he was wounded.
But he said that I just cause trouble.
Well, it all depends on the person.
I know there are both wounded and unwounded people in this world.
But I didn't know that there are wounded people who don't want to be healed.
And?
Yeah?
What do you wanna do?
I'll...
You wanna heal them, right? So heal them.
Is that the right thing to do?
Worry about whether it's the right thing to do or not after you actually heal them.
Right!
See ya!
Bye-bye!
Let's go home!
That's...
Toshihiko?
Kobato...
Nursery is over? Are you going home now?
Yeah, but not yet.
Do you like swings?
Yeah, but I don't really like them that much.
But I have to wait here a bit more because Mom's not home yet.
She's at work.
She's at work, huh?
But...
She works really hard!
And even though it's been hard since the divorce, she still makes me breakfast!
And she's really nice! Really!
That's great!
Aren't you gonna say that it's horrible?
What is?
Toshihiko, is your mother late again?
Yeah.
I see. It's good of you to not be selfish.
Again today, Toshihiko? You're such a good boy for waiting for her.
It'd be nice if your mom thought of you a little more, right?
Yeah.
Even if she's busy at work, isn't this a bit too much?
Everyone says she's a bad mom.
That she's a poor mother.
A poor mother?
They're wrong! She works her hardest!
Really! She's a great mom!
That's wonderful.
It's wonderful that you have such a great and hardworking mom.
Really?
Yes! She's a great mom.
What's wrong?
Does something hurt?
No.
Really?
There's something in here!
But why?
It's from that Toshihiko kid.
Toshihiko?
Hey!
Swing, Kobato!
Toshihiko, you're really good at this!
Hey, keep trying!
He was really happy that you praised his mom and were kind to him.
I was... kind to him?
If your heart's not in the right place,
kindness won't be enough to heal people.
Just keep doing what you did there.
Right.
I'll work hard and keep trying to collect people's wounded hearts!
Wait a minute!
That makes it sound like you're gonna go around wounding them yourself!
Then... their healed hearts?
That makes it sound like you're gonna take them away right after you heal them.
Then... what should I call these?
Jeez, you're annoying!
They look like konpeito, so just call 'em that.
Konpeito...
All right! I'll call them konpeito!
Hey, Kobato.
Yeah?
Abandoning me was really bad, but the rest was great.
You get 100 points.
Keep up the good work, Kobato!
Right!
I'll do my best!
Don't slack off because you got 100!
But you said to keep up the good work!
That's not what I meant!
Then what should I do?
Fine! No 100 after all!
No fair!
Even though we all want to fly,
we're being deceived by gravity.
In reality, everybody can already fly.
The reason why that child looks so sad
might be because she left her shadow somewhere.
If so...
If telling you "Thank you",
or hearing "Thank you" just makes you smile,
then doing those things will make me happy.
And they'll make you happy too.
Don't worry, we're together.
It's mysterious as to why tears roll down
even though I'm happy.
Next
...The Rain's Gift.